

ELOCHUKWU AROH

elochukwuaroh@gmail.com | +1 587-357-2325 | Winnipeg, Manitoba R2K3P6

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- https://elochukwuaroh.com/
- https://github.com/aroh-elochukwu
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/elochukwu-aroh-b5a71617b/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate Software Developer, with over 3 years of experience building and maintaining mobile and web applications. Eager to join your challenging work environment, utilizing my technical skills in creating responsive, user-friendly, and customer-oriented projects with laser focus attention to specications.

SKILLS

- Code and Quality Standards
- Strong Communication and Interpersonal Skills
- API Design and Development
- Source and Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Eagerness to Learn New Technologies
- Scrum Methodology

- Bug Fixes
- Programming Languages: Java, C#, .Net, Javascript, React, Angular, Node
- Databases: Oracle, MongoDB
- RDMS Development and SQL
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Project/Organizational management tools: Jira, Slack, Asana

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer | UpWork Inc - Remote

12/2022 - CURRENT

 Collaborated with a team of 5 developers to deliver on Client's Application needs/requirements with today's best technology.

Software Developer | PCL Construction - Nisku, AB

01/2020 - 11/2022

- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Developed software for both desktop and mobile operating systems.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Responding to technical support requests. Investigating,

troubleshooting, resolving bugs, and applying hotfixes to live software when necessary.

• Creating and maintaining technical documentation.

Software Developer Intern | Bit Space Develoment - 10/2019 - 12/2019 Winnipeg, MB

- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.
- Maintained and added feature updates to legacy projects using React, Angular, C# programming language.
- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various projects.
- Assisted with design and development of Construction Safety Association of Manitoba App.

Data Analyst | Delta State Contributory Health 04/2017 - 12/2018 Commission

- Coordinated statistical data analysis, design and information flow.
- Created various Excel documents to assist with pulling metrics data and presenting information to stakeholders for concise explanations of best placement for needed resources.
- Produced monthly reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs.

Hardware Engineering Intern | Hi-tech Distributors 01/2015 - 06/2015

- Hardware maintenance and repairs.
- Installation of devices purchased by customers.

EDUCATION

Benson Idahosa University, Edo State, Nigeria

07/2016

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Manitoba Institute of Trades And Technology, Winnipeg, MB

12/2019

Diploma: Software Development

CERTIFICATIONS

- Scrum Foundations certification from Scrum Alliance, Oct 2022
- Project Management Course, July 2016
- Cyber-Security Ethics in Health Information Management by the National Health Insurance Scheme, November 2019
- Teamwork and Work Place Ethics by Streamline Group, April 2019